class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> letter_and_number_analogy = [



  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. Agra is to Uttar Pradesh as Chennai is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Tamil Nadu",
        "B) Karnataka",
        "C) Andhra Pradesh",
        "D) Kerala",
        "E) Gujarat"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "In this analogy, Agra is a famous city in Uttar Pradesh, so Chennai is the counterpart in Tamil Nadu. The correct answer is A) Tamil Nadu."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "2. Delhi is to New Delhi as Mumbai is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Maharashtra",
        "B) Gujarat",
        "C) Goa",
        "D) Madhya Pradesh",
        "E) Rajasthan"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "New Delhi is the capital city of India, which is situated within the territory of Delhi. Similarly, Mumbai is the capital city of Maharashtra. The correct answer is A) Maharashtra."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "3. Bengaluru is to Karnataka as Jaipur is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Rajasthan",
        "B) Haryana",
        "C) Punjab",
        "D) Bihar",
        "E) Jharkhand"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Bengaluru is the capital city of Karnataka, so Jaipur is the counterpart in Rajasthan. The correct answer is A) Rajasthan."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "4. Mahatma Gandhi is to India as Nelson Mandela is to:",
      options: [
        "A) South Africa",
        "B) United Kingdom",
        "C) United States",
        "D) Canada",
        "E) Australia"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Mahatma Gandhi was a prominent figure in the Indian independence movement, and he is associated with India. Similarly, Nelson Mandela is associated with South Africa. The correct answer is A) South Africa."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "5. Delhi is to India as Washington, D.C. is to:",
      options: [
        "A) United States",
        "B) United Kingdom",
        "C) France",
        "D) Canada",
        "E) Australia"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Delhi is the capital city of India, and Washington, D.C. is the capital city of the United States. The correct answer is A) United States."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "6. Mumbai is to Maharashtra as Kolkata is to:",
      options: [
        "A) West Bengal",
        "B) Odisha",
        "C) Bihar",
        "D) Jharkhand",
        "E) Assam"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Mumbai is the capital city of Maharashtra, so Kolkata is the counterpart in West Bengal. The correct answer is A) West Bengal."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "7. Taj Mahal is to Agra as Hawa Mahal is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Jaipur",
        "B) Udaipur",
        "C) Jodhpur",
        "D) Varanasi",
        "E) Bikaner"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Taj Mahal is a famous monument in Agra, and Hawa Mahal is a famous monument in Jaipur, Rajasthan. The correct answer is A) Jaipur."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "8. Kolkata is to West Bengal as Lucknow is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Uttar Pradesh",
        "B) Bihar",
        "C) Madhya Pradesh",
        "D) Haryana",
        "E) Punjab"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Kolkata is the capital city of West Bengal, so Lucknow is the counterpart in Uttar Pradesh. The correct answer is A) Uttar Pradesh."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "9. Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam is to India as Sir Isaac Newton is to:",
      options: [
        "A) United Kingdom",
        "B) United States",
        "C) Germany",
        "D) France",
        "E) Italy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam was the President of India and a renowned scientist, and he is associated with India. Similarly, Sir Isaac Newton is associated with the United Kingdom. The correct answer is A) United Kingdom."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "10. Goa is to India as Maldives is to:",
      options: [
        "A) South Asia",
        "B) Southeast Asia",
        "C) Middle East",
        "D) East Africa",
        "E) Pacific Islands"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Goa is a state in India known for its coastal location, and Maldives is an island nation located in South Asia. The correct answer is A) South Asia."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "11. Bollywood is to India as Hollywood is to:",
      options: [
        "A) United States",
        "B) United Kingdom",
        "C) France",
        "D) Canada",
        "E) Australia"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Bollywood is the film industry in India, and Hollywood is the film industry in the United States. The correct answer is A) United States."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "12. Rabindranath Tagore is to India as William Shakespeare is to:",
      options: [
        "A) United Kingdom",
        "B) United States",
        "C) Germany",
        "D) France",
        "E) Italy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Rabindranath Tagore was a famous Indian poet, and William Shakespeare is a famous English playwright. Both are associated with their respective countries. The correct answer is A) United Kingdom."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "13. Red Fort is to Delhi as Gateway of India is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Mumbai",
        "B) Chennai",
        "C) Kolkata",
        "D) Hyderabad",
        "E) Bangalore"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Red Fort is a historic monument in Delhi, and Gateway of India is a famous monument in Mumbai. The correct answer is A) Mumbai."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "14. Indira Gandhi is to India as Angela Merkel is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Germany",
        "B) United States",
        "C) United Kingdom",
        "D) France",
        "E) Italy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Indira Gandhi was a former Prime Minister of India, and Angela Merkel was a former Chancellor of Germany. The correct answer is A) Germany."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "15. Mumbai is to Maharashtra as Hyderabad is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Telangana",
        "B) Andhra Pradesh",
        "C) Karnataka",
        "D) Kerala",
        "E) Tamil Nadu"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Mumbai is the capital city of Maharashtra, so Hyderabad is the capital city of Telangana. The correct answer is A) Telangana."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "16. Rajiv Gandhi is to India as John F. Kennedy is to:",
      options: [
        "A) United States",
        "B) United Kingdom",
        "C) Germany",
        "D) France",
        "E) Italy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Rajiv Gandhi was a former Prime Minister of India, and John F. Kennedy was a former President of the United States. The correct answer is A) United States."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "17. Golden Temple is to Amritsar as Mecca is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Saudi Arabia",
        "B) Iran",
        "C) Iraq",
        "D) Turkey",
        "E) Jordan"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "The Golden Temple is a famous Sikh shrine in Amritsar, India, and Mecca is a holy city in Saudi Arabia for Muslims. The correct answer is A) Saudi Arabia."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "18. Indian National Congress is to India as Conservative Party is to:",
      options: [
        "A) United Kingdom",
        "B) United States",
        "C) Germany",
        "D) France",
        "E) Italy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "The Indian National Congress is a major political party in India, and the Conservative Party is a political party in the United Kingdom. The correct answer is A) United Kingdom."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "19. Jallianwala Bagh is to Amritsar as Tiananmen Square is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Beijing",
        "B) Shanghai",
        "C) Hong Kong",
        "D) Guangzhou",
        "E) Chengdu"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Jallianwala Bagh is a historic site in Amritsar, India, and Tiananmen Square is a famous square in Beijing, China. The correct answer is A) Beijing."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "20. Lata Mangeshkar is to India as Celine Dion is to:",
      options: [
        "A) Canada",
        "B) United States",
        "C) United Kingdom",
        "D) France",
        "E) Italy"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Lata Mangeshkar is a legendary Indian playback singer, and Celine Dion is a renowned Canadian singer. The correct answer is A) Canada."
  ),

];